Guide to the Standing Committee on Professional Awareness, Yale University Library, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Standing Committee on Professional Awareness, Yale University Library, records
1986-2004
RU 154
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6
The records consist of memoranda, minutes, agendas, videotapes, and correspondence documenting the operations and activities of the Standing Committee on Professional Awareness (SCOPA) at Yale University Library.
Yale University. Library
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-F (YRG 32-F), Records of Yale University Library staff organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of memoranda, minutes, agendas, videotapes, and correspondence documenting the operations and activities of the Standing Committee on Professional Awareness (SCOPA) at Yale University Library.
Academic libraries; Committees; Librarians; Yale University. Library
- Records of SCOPA and co-chair subject files, 1986-1993; Accession 1994-A-126 (Box 1–4)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2028
  Scope and Contents
  No online inventory. Inventory available in repository.
- Records of SCOPA and co-chair subject files, 1994; Accession 1996-A-056 (Box 1)
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2029
  No inventory available.
- Records of SCOPA and co-chair subject files, 1995-1996; Accession 1997-A-054 (Box 1)
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2031
- Records of the chair of the Standing Committee on Professional Awareness, 1999-2000; Accession 2001-A-123
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2035
  - General, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Budget, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Grants, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mentoring program, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Orientation for New Librarians, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Review of promotion process, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Scholarly Electronic Publishing in the 21stCentury: Trends, Models, and Impacts on Information Services. A Three Part Series", 2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Grant records, 1996-1999; Accession 2002-A-134 (Box 1)
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2034
- Committee records maintained by, Nancy Kuhl, 2004; Accession 2005-A-167 (Box 1)
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2039
- Records of the Standing Committee on Professional Awareness, 1995-1996, 2000-2001; Accession 2006-A-209
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2037
  - 1995-1996
    - Information on SCOPA, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Grants - Letters to Recipients (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Grant Proposals, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - SCOPA Grant Proposals, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 4 - 5)
    - Scopa Grants, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Scopa, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Notices and Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - New Professional Staff Orientation, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Agendas (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Minutes (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Copyright Forum (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Meeting Notices (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Calendar Project (Jocelyn Tipton) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Yale Digital Imaging Forum (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Programs (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Transitional Meeting (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Copy of Talk of the Nation Program featuring Ann Okerson, 2001 June 22 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 2000-2001
    - General, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Forums, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - SCOPA, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Budget, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Mentoring (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Pub Page (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Questions for Alice, 2000 September 26 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Grants, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - New Librarian Orientation (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Orientation (April & October), 2001 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Digital Projects Symposium (Box 2, Folder 29)
- SCOPA Copyright Forum [videorecordings], 1996; Accession 2007-A-118
  The materials are open for research.
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - Professor Ralph S. Brown, 1996 January 9; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
    - Use copy, 1996 January 9; videotape (VHS) (Box 1U)
  - Karen Hersey, 1996 March 21; videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
    - Use copy, 1996 March 21; videotape (VHS) (Box 2U)
  - Copyright Discussion, Yale Law School featuring Susan Kornfield, 1996 April 29; videotape (VHS) (Box 3)
    - Use copy, 1996 April 29; videotape (VHS) (Box 3U)
- Correspondence, memoranda, reports, and grant applications maintained by the committee chair, SCOPA, 2001-2003; Accession 2007-A-184
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2038
  - Forum, orientation, meetings, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Grants and orientation, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Grants, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - New librarian orientation, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Records maintained by Diane Turner, committee sponsor, SCOPA, circa 1988-1997; Accession 2007-A-185
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2032
  - Committees and grants, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes and correspondence, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memoranda, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Nominations, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and minutes, 1988-1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Grants, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 7 - 8)
  - Correspondence and minutes, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Nominations, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Questionnaire, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Agendas and minutes, 2005; Accession 2008-A-037
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2041
  - Agendas and minutes, 2005 (Box 1)